A Guide to the Virginia Association of Educational Opportunity Program Personnel (VAEOPP) Records, 1970-2015
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Virginia Association of Educational Opportunity Program Personnel (VAEOPP) Records, 1970-2015
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Virginia Association of Educational Opportunity Program
Ms1989-003
5.5 Cubic Feet 5 boxes
The collections is organized into seven series: Board and Administrative Records, Conference Material, Membership Material, Correspondence, Newsletters and Other Publications, Miscellaneous Material, and Media. The collection includes, but is not limited to: meeting minute and agendas, committee reports, conference planning documents and programs, forms, organizational correspondence, membership lists, publications, and memorabilia.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The original material in the collection was donated to Special Collections in January 1989. Material was added to the collection in 1990, 1991, and 2012. Additional donations were received in 2013 and 2015.
Historical Information
The Virginia Association of Educational Opportunity Program Personnel (VAEOPP) was established in 1975 as an organization to bring together those who are professionally involved in broadening accessibility to and success in the formal post-secondary education of economically or socially disadvantaged Virginians.
Scope and Content
The collections is organized into seven series: Board and Administrative Records, Conference Material, Membership Material, Correspondence, Newsletters and Other Publications, Miscellaneous Material, and Media.
Series I: Board and Administrative Records includes by-laws and constitutions, governmental and legislative material, strategic plans, meeting agendas, meeting minutes, board members, election material, committees, board reports, committee reports, scholarship recipients, scholarship applications, guidelines, and qualifications, surveys, proposals and recommendations, awards and recognition, student special services material, budget information, financial information, bank statements, receipts, fiscal management manuals, and miscellaneous forms.
Series II: Conference Material consists of conference programs, evaluations and proposals, registration and attendance, pamphlets and fliers, schedules, a speech, and a planning manual.
Series III: Membership Material contains personnel directories, membership information, membership applications, program manuals, resumes, and activities.
Series IV: Correspondence is composed of program personnel mailing, letters, notes, and memos.
Series V: Newsletters and Other Publications includes newspaper clippings, bulletins, updates, expository essays, as well as association newsletters and journals.
Series VI: Notes and Handouts consists of transportation information, notes, reference manuals, fliers, and a poem.
Series VII: Media includes unrestricted electronic files from a flash drive donated with the 2012 accrual. Files date from approximately 2003 to 2011.
Arrangement
Series I: Board and Administrative Records is arranged by type of material. Series II: Conference Material is arranged by type of material. Series III: Membership Material is arranged by type of material. Series IV: Correspondence is arranged chronologically by date. Series V: Newsletters and Other Publications is arranged chronologically by date. Series VI: Notes and Handouts is arranged by type of material. Series VII: Media files were left in their original order.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
The collection contained two unidentified Hi8 video tapes and a flash drive. The video tapes were removed to the accession file and are available on request. Please note: Special Collections does not have a player for these tapes. Unrestricted materials from the flash drive are available on the CD in the Series VII: Media folder.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Series I: Board and Administrative Records
  - By-laws and Constitutions (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1, Folder 2)
  - Governmental and Legislative Material (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Strategic Plans (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board Meeting Agendas (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting Agendas (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 6, Folder 7)
  - State Meeting Agendas (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Business Meeting Agendas (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Meeting Agendas (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 11, Folder 12, Folder 13, Folder 14)
  - Board and Committee Meeting Minutes (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 15, Folder 16)
  - State Meeting Minutes (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 17, Folder 18, Folder 19, Folder 20)
  - Business Meeting Minutes (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21, Folder 22)
  - Minutes (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Board Members (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Election Material (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Committees (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Presidential Reports (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27, Folder 28, Folder 29)
  - President-elect and Past President Reports (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Officers and Representatives Reports (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Legislative Committee and Nominations and Elections Committee Reports (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Membership Committee and Scholarship Committee Reports (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Development Committee and Emerging Leaders Program Reports (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Conference Committee and Banquet and Facilities Committee Reports (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Trio Achievers Committee and Awards and Recognition Committee Reports (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Public Relations Committee and Communications Committee Reports (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Finance Committee and Archives Committee Reports (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous Committee Reports (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Scholarship Material (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Surveys (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Proposals and Recommendations (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Awards and Recognition (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Student Special Services Material (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fiscal Management Manuals (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Forms (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - State Meeting Minutes, October 2012 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - State Meeting Minutes, March and October 2013 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - President's Papers (Christie Hardbarger), 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - President's Papers (Christie Hardbarger), 2012 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Proclamation, City of Roanoke (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Proclamation holder, Salem (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Proclamation, City of Salem (Box 5)
  - Certificate of Recognition, Trio Day, 2004 (Box 5)
- Series II: Conference Material
  - Conference Programs, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conference Programs, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Conference Programs, 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conference Programs, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Conference Programs, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conference Programs, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conference Programs, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conference Programs, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Conference Evaluations and Proposals (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Conference Registration and Attendance (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Conference Pamphlets and Fliers (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Conference Material (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Conference Materials, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Conference Materials, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Conference Materials, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series III: Membership Material
  - Personnel Directories (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 20, Folder 21, Folder 22)
  - Membership Information (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 23, Folder 24)
  - Membership Applications (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 25, Folder 26)
  - Program Manuals (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Resumes and Activities (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series IV: Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Jun., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, Jul.-Dec., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2009, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series V: Newsletters and Other Publications (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Notes and Handouts (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Media (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Scope and Content
  The 2011 donation to the collection included a flash drive with organizational records. The CD in the collection includes unrestricted materials from the flash drive.